Preliminary Inventory to the Alan H. Nichols Papers, 1917-1946
Hoover Institution Archives
Alan H. Nichols Papers,
1917-1946
92080
Nichols, Alan H., d. 1918
4 manuscript boxes (1.2 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, military documents, clippings, and photographs, relating to American volunteer ambulance drivers in France, and to American volunteer aviators in the French army, during World War I. Includes Nichols family correspondence relating to Alan H. Nichols, and correspondence and military documents of Nichols' brother, John R. Nichols, relating to American volunteer ambulance drivers in the Balkans, Italy and France, and to American Tank Corps operations in France, during World War I.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Access Points
World War, 1914-1918--Campaigns--France.; World War, 1914-1918--Aerial operations.; World War, 1914-1918--Medical and sanitary affairs.; France. Armee. Service aeronautique. Escadrille n. 85.; United States. Army. Tank Corps. Battalion, 344th.; United States. Army. American Expeditionary Forces.; American Field Service.; World War, 1914-1918.; United States--Armed Forces.; France.; Nichols, John R.
Container List
- Letters by Alan H. Nichols, 1917-1918 (Box 1)
- Typed transcripts of letters by Alan H. Nichols, 1917-1918 (Box 2)
- Letters to Alan H. Nichols, 1917-1918 (Box 3)
- Military documents of Alan H. Nichols, 1917-1923
- Nichols family correspondence regarding Alan H. Nichols, 1917-1926
- Miscellany regarding Alan H. Nichols, 1917-1946
- Correspondence and military documents of John R. Nichols, 1917-1920
- Typed transcripts of letters by John R. Nichols, 1917-1918
- Clippings and newspaper issues, 1917-1919
- Photographs, ca. 1917-1918 (Box 4)